

Miroslav Gannoha

Senior Software Engineer

Email:

miroslav.gannoha@gmail.com

Github:

github.com/MiroslavGannoha

Website

www.miroslav-gannoha.me

Professional Skills

Languages

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript

Frontend frameworks

ReactJS, NextJS, Mobx, Immer, Recoil, Emotion, TailwindCSS, ThreeJS

Backend

NodeJS, Firebase

Education

2005 - 2010

BBA: Business And Managerial Economics, Engineering

Kyiv National University Of Technologies & Design - Kyiv

Interests

- Technologies, software development, blockchain, geopolitics
- Gaming, esports, streams
- Traveling, exploring new locations and cultures
- Sports activities bicycling, running, surfing, football, other

Personal Profile

I am a creative, open-minded & responsible senior software engineer. Eight years of experience in building web applications. I'm quality-driven but can balance between speed & quality to meet deadlines. Skills in responsive & cross-browser development, designing UI & UX, improving performance, testing, mentoring.

Career Summary

Senior Software Engineer

Oct 2020 - Current

Fluxon, San Francisco, California, US (REMOTE)

Moonwalk (Orbit) moonwalk-demo.fluxon.dev

- Worked on improvements and new features for a virtual events platform (3D app in a browser) which were required to host events for clients. Proposed many own ideas like ways to implement the auditorium feature
- Built the new chat with a full feature set history, user list, DMs, global & a scene chat, new messages indicators, notifications & other
- Optimized the chat to work with hundreds & thousands of users using advanced techniques such as - buffering, lazy loading, memoization, optimistic updates, lazy rooms creation & preventing redundant re-renders
- Initiated and refactored the most entangled parts of the code which reduced the number of lines significantly and simplified the maintenance of the project
- Created the event emitter to improve communications between different parts of the code

Zapier zapier.com

- Helped to prepare and launch a new blog rapidly fixing all critical issues for a short period of time before the launch
- · Initiated and implemented image optimizations for the entire blog
- Identified and fixed package management versioning issue which reduced bundle size by 30%
- Together with the team built a new homepage and successfully launched it
- Built custom slider component from scratch which was required for the homepage
- Proposed and added UX improvements slide autoplay and homepage animations

Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2017 - May 2020

Invictus Gurus, Dallas, Texas, US (REMOTE)

Law Pilot lawpilot.com

- Built from the ground up front-end part of the law firm management portal and led it successfully to production.
- Designed the UI and implemented various views(pages) or implemented from the mock-ups
- Iterated over UI and UX improvements from the customer feedback
- Worked together with BE developers on designing server endpoints for the client code
- Improved app loading time by 25% by splitting app bundle into chunks
- · Implemented drag and drop page for questionnaire builder

Software Engineer Feb 2014 - Mar 2017

Epam, Kyiv, Ukraine

Junior Software Developer Apr 2013 - Feb 2014

Anotheria Solutions, Kyiv, Ukraine

Junior Software Developer Feb 2012 - Apr 2013

Webbylab, Kyiv, Ukraine